// db.getCollection('gamesets').find({});


/* 1 */
{
	"_id": ObjectId("595d56b4b2a05875b2da13c7"),
	"hint": "“The unexamined life is not worth living” ",
	"answer": "Socrates",
	"gametype": "whosaysthis",
	"question": "Who says this?",
	"__v": 0
}

/* 2 */
{
	"_id": ObjectId("595d56e2b2a05875b2da13c8"),
	"hint": "“The life of man (in a state of nature) is solitary, poor, nasty, brutish, and short”",
	"answer": "Thomas Hobbes",
	"gametype": "whosaysthis",
	"question": "Who says this?",
	"__v": 0
}

/* 3 */
{
	"_id": ObjectId("595d56f5b2a05875b2da13c9"),
	"hint": "“I think therefore I am” (“Cogito, ergo sum”)",
	"answer": "René Descartes",
	"gametype": "whosaysthis",
	"question": "Who says this?",
	"__v": 0
}

/* 4 */
{
	"_id": ObjectId("595d5711b2a05875b2da13ca"),
	"hint": "“One cannot step twice in the same river”",
	"answer": "Heraclitus",
	"gametype": "whosaysthis",
	"question": "Who says this?",
	"__v": 0
}

/* 5 */
{
	"_id": ObjectId("595d5724b2a05875b2da13cb"),
	"hint": "“No man's knowledge here can go beyond his experience”",
	"answer": "John Locke",
	"gametype": "whosaysthis",
	"question": "Who says this?",
	"__v": 0
}

/* 6 */
{
	"_id": ObjectId("595d573fb2a05875b2da13cc"),
	"hint": "“God is not willing to do everything, and thus take away our free will and that share of glory which belongs to us”",
	"answer": "Machiavelli",
	"gametype": "whosaysthis",
	"question": "Who says this?",
	"__v": 0
}

/* 7 */
{
	"_id": ObjectId("595d576bb2a05875b2da13cd"),
	"hint": "“Even while they teach, men learn” ",
	"answer": "Seneca the Younger",
	"gametype": "whosaysthis",
	"question": "Who says this?",
	"__v": 0
}

/* 8 */
{
	"_id": ObjectId("595d577ab2a05875b2da13ce"),
	"hint": "“There is only one good, knowledge, and one evil, ignorance”",
	"answer": "Socrates",
	"gametype": "whosaysthis",
	"question": "Who says this?",
	"__v": 0
}

/* 9 */
{
	"_id": ObjectId("595d5837b2a05875b2da13cf"),
	"hint": "“If God did not exist, it would be necessary to invent Him”",
	"answer": "Voltaire",
	"gametype": "whosaysthis",
	"question": "Who says this?",
	"__v": 0
}

/* 10 */
{
	"_id": ObjectId("595d5858b2a05875b2da13d0"),
	"hint": "“One cannot conceive anything so strange and so implausible that it has not already been said by one philosopher or another”",
	"answer": "René Descartes",
	"gametype": "whosaysthis",
	"question": "Who says this?",
	"__v": 0
}

/* 11 */
{
	"_id": ObjectId("595d586bb2a05875b2da13d1"),
	"hint": "“Leisure is the mother of philosophy”",
	"answer": "Thomas Hobbes",
	"gametype": "whosaysthis",
	"question": "Who says this?",
	"__v": 0
}

/* 12 */
{
	"_id": ObjectId("595d5880b2a05875b2da13d2"),
	"hint": "“We are what we repeatedly do. Excellence, then, is not an act, but a habit” ",
	"answer": " Aristotle",
	"gametype": "whosaysthis",
	"question": "Who says this?",
	"__v": 0
}

/* 13 */
{
	"_id": ObjectId("595d588fb2a05875b2da13d3"),
	"hint": "“The mind is furnished with ideas by experience alone”",
	"answer": "John Locke",
	"gametype": "whosaysthis",
	"question": "Who says this?",
	"__v": 0
}

/* 14 */
{
	"_id": ObjectId("595d58a1b2a05875b2da13d4"),
	"hint": "“He who is unable to live in society, or who has no need because he is sufficient for himself, must be either a beast or a god”",
	"answer": "Aristotle",
	"gametype": "whosaysthis",
	"question": "Who says this?",
	"__v": 0
}

/* 15 */
{
	"_id": ObjectId("595d58b4b2a05875b2da13d5"),
	"hint": "“You can discover more about a person in an hour of play than in a year of conversation”",
	"answer": "Plato",
	"gametype": "whosaysthis",
	"question": "Who says this?",
	"__v": 0
}

/* 16 */
{
	"_id": ObjectId("595d58d0b2a05875b2da13d6"),
	"hint": "“Religion is the sign of the oppressed ... it is the opium of the people”",
	"answer": "Karl Marx",
	"gametype": "whosaysthis",
	"question": "Who says this?",
	"__v": 0
}

/* 17 */
{
	"_id": ObjectId("595d5925b2a05875b2da13d7"),
	"hint": "“Happiness is the highest good”",
	"answer": "Aristotle",
	"gametype": "whosaysthis",
	"question": "Who says this?",
	"__v": 0
}

/* 18 */
{
	"_id": ObjectId("595d5939b2a05875b2da13d8"),
	"hint": "“The greater the difficulty, the more glory in surmounting it”",
	"answer": "Epicurus",
	"gametype": "whosaysthis",
	"question": "Who says this?",
	"__v": 0
}

/* 19 */
{
	"_id": ObjectId("595d594cb2a05875b2da13d9"),
	"hint": "“Man is condemned to be free”",
	"answer": "Jean-Paul Sartre",
	"gametype": "whosaysthis",
	"question": "Who says this?",
	"__v": 0
}

/* 20 */
{
	"_id": ObjectId("595d595cb2a05875b2da13da"),
	"hint": "“It is one thing to show a man that he is in error, and another to put him in possession of truth”",
	"answer": "John Locke",
	"gametype": "whosaysthis",
	"question": "Who says this?",
	"__v": 0
}

/* 21 */
{
	"_id": ObjectId("595d596eb2a05875b2da13db"),
	"hint": "“That man is wisest who, like Socrates, realizes that his wisdom is worthless” ",
	"answer": "Plato",
	"gametype": "whosaysthis",
	"question": "Who says this?",
	"__v": 0
}

/* 22 */
{
	"_id": ObjectId("595d598fb2a05875b2da13dc"),
	"hint": "“The only thing I know is that I know nothing”",
	"answer": "Socrates",
	"gametype": "whosaysthis",
	"question": "Who says this?",
	"__v": 0
}

/* 23 */
{
	"_id": ObjectId("595d599fb2a05875b2da13dd"),
	"hint": "“All is for the best in the best of all possible worlds”",
	"answer": "Voltaire",
	"gametype": "whosaysthis",
	"question": "Who says this?",
	"__v": 0
}

/* 24 */
{
	"_id": ObjectId("595d59b9b2a05875b2da13de"),
	"hint": "“If you would be a real seeker after truth, it is necessary that at least once in your life you doubt, as far as possible, all things”",
	"answer": "René Descartes",
	"gametype": "whosaysthis",
	"question": "Who says this?",
	"__v": 0
}

/* 25 */
{
	"_id": ObjectId("595d59c9b2a05875b2da13df"),
	"hint": "“Happiness lies in virtuous activity, and perfect happiness lies in the best activity, which is contemplative”",
	"answer": "Aristotle",
	"gametype": "whosaysthis",
	"question": "Who says this?",
	"__v": 0
}

/* 26 */
{
	"_id": ObjectId("595d59ddb2a05875b2da13e0"),
	"hint": "“Virtue is nothing else than right reason”",
	"answer": "Seneca the Younger",
	"gametype": "whosaysthis",
	"question": "Who says this?",
	"__v": 0
}

/* 27 */
{
	"_id": ObjectId("595d59eeb2a05875b2da13e1"),
	"hint": "“Freedom is secured not by the fulfilling of one's desires, but by the removal of desire”",
	"answer": "Epictetus",
	"gametype": "whosaysthis",
	"question": "Who says this?",
	"__v": 0
}

/* 28 */
{
	"_id": ObjectId("595d5a07b2a05875b2da13e2"),
	"hint": "“The brave man is he who overcomes not only his enemies but his pleasures”",
	"answer": "Democritus",
	"gametype": "whosaysthis",
	"question": "Who says this?",
	"__v": 0
}

/* 29 */
{
	"_id": ObjectId("595d5a1fb2a05875b2da13e3"),
	"hint": "“To do as one would be done by, and to love one's neighbour as oneself, constitute the ideal perfection of utilitarian morality”",
	"answer": "John Stuart Mill",
	"gametype": "whosaysthis",
	"question": "Who says this?",
	"__v": 0
}

/* 30 */
{
	"_id": ObjectId("595d5a38b2a05875b2da13e4"),
	"hint": "“Everything that exists is born for no reason, carries on living through weakness, and dies by accident”",
	"answer": " Jean-Paul Sartre",
	"gametype": "whosaysthis",
	"question": "Who says this?",
	"__v": 0
}

/* 31 */
{
	"_id": ObjectId("595d5a4ab2a05875b2da13e5"),
	"hint": "“Man is the measure of all things”",
	"answer": "Protagoras",
	"gametype": "whosaysthis",
	"question": "Who says this?",
	"__v": 0
}

/* 32 */
{
	"_id": ObjectId("595d5a58b2a05875b2da13e6"),
	"hint": "“The mind is furnished with ideas by experience alone”",
	"answer": "John Locke",
	"gametype": "whosaysthis",
	"question": "Who says this?",
	"__v": 0
}

/* 33 */
{
	"_id": ObjectId("595d5a83b2a05875b2da13e7"),
	"hint": "“We are too weak to discover the truth by reason alone”",
	"answer": "St. Augustine",
	"gametype": "whosaysthis",
	"question": "Who says this?",
	"__v": 0
}

/* 34 */
{
	"_id": ObjectId("595d709a121da97d3f268d78"),
	"hint": "\"One of the simple ingredients of the visible world, such as air, earth, fire or water. Or hidden tiny simple units called ‘atoms’. We can explain things without reference to the gods. \"",
	"answer": "Early Naturalists ",
	"gametype": "whichperiodisthisfrom",
	"question": "Which period is this from?",
	"__v": 0
}

/* 35 */
{
	"_id": ObjectId("595d70da121da97d3f268d79"),
	"hint": "\"Since reality is hidden, reason is more reliable. Maths is the key, or we can deduce the existence of some very simple single pure reality.\"",
	"answer": "Early Rationalists",
	"gametype": "whichperiodisthisfrom",
	"question": "Which period is this from?",
	"__v": 0
}

/* 36 */
{
	"_id": ObjectId("595d7439d967077fc865d76d"),
	"hint": "\"Relativism is indeed true, so morality is invented for our own convenience (usually selfish), and neither our sense nor our reason can be trusted \"",
	"answer": "Athenian sophists",
	"gametype": "whichperiodisthisfrom",
	"question": "Which period is this from?",
	"__v": 0
}

/* 37 */
{
	"_id": ObjectId("595d7488d967077fc865d76e"),
	"hint": "\"Although both senses and reason are riddled with doubts, right thinking will lead to truth, and moral goodness will naturally follow from a perception of the truth. \"",
	"answer": "Socrates",
	"gametype": "whichperiodisthisfrom",
	"question": "Which period is this from?",
	"__v": 0
}

/* 38 */
{
	"_id": ObjectId("595d74a0d967077fc865d76f"),
	"hint": "\"Reason shows us that there must be a set of fixed and unchanging ideas, which not only explain our highest ideals, but also the ordinary way we understand concepts and language \"",
	"answer": "Platonic",
	"gametype": "whichperiodisthisfrom",
	"question": "Which period is this from?",
	"__v": 0
}

/* 39 */
{
	"_id": ObjectId("595d74b2d967077fc865d770"),
	"hint": "The essence of the things we experience are eternal and unchanging, so that we can come to understand the truth, purpose and virtue of each thing by a careful combination of observation and analysis",
	"answer": "Aristotle",
	"gametype": "whichperiodisthisfrom",
	"question": "Which period is this from?",
	"__v": 0
}

/* 40 */
{
	"_id": ObjectId("595d74ebd967077fc865d771"),
	"hint": "For every argument invented there seems to be a plausible counter-argument, so the best solution is just to become very passive, which brings great peace of mind ",
	"answer": "Sceptics",
	"gametype": "whichperiodisthisfrom",
	"question": "Which period is this from?",
	"__v": 0
}

/* 41 */
{
	"_id": ObjectId("595d7506d967077fc865d773"),
	"hint": "\"For every argument invented there seems to be a plausible counter-argument, so the best solution is just to become very passive, which brings great peace of mind\"",
	"answer": "Sceptics",
	"gametype": "whichperiodisthisfrom",
	"question": "Which period is this from?",
	"__v": 0
}

/* 42 */
{
	"_id": ObjectId("595d7535d967077fc865d774"),
	"hint": "\"We should abandon conventional rules and follow our own personal desires, though experience shows that the best life is not self-indulgent, but very simple and restrained \"",
	"answer": "Cynics",
	"gametype": "whichperiodisthisfrom",
	"question": "Which period is this from?",
	"__v": 0
}

/* 43 */
{
	"_id": ObjectId("595d7556d967077fc865d775"),
	"hint": "\"The naturalists do seem to give the best explanations of existence, so we should accept their reliance on the senses and their belief in atoms. The best life is therefore the one that brings happiness for us as physical creatures, which is a life of cautious pleasure\"",
	"answer": "Epicureans ",
	"gametype": "whichperiodisthisfrom",
	"question": "Which period is this from?",
	"__v": 0
}

/* 44 */
{
	"_id": ObjectId("595d7577d967077fc865d776"),
	"hint": "\"Knowledge must come from a combination of senses and reason. We must accept the material world, but it is designed and guided by gods. We must therefore live in accordance with nature, and learn a quiet acceptance of even the cruellest natural events \"",
	"answer": "Stoics ",
	"gametype": "whichperiodisthisfrom",
	"question": "Which period is this from?",
	"__v": 0
}

/* 45 */
{
	"_id": ObjectId("595d758ad967077fc865d777"),
	"hint": "\"We can now see that Plato’s forms are religious in character, and exist eternally in the mind of God. The form of pure goodness sought by Plato is the same as God himself \"",
	"answer": "Neo-Platonists",
	"gametype": "whichperiodisthisfrom",
	"question": "Which period is this from?",
	"__v": 0
}

/* 46 */
{
	"_id": ObjectId("595d768dd967077fc865d778"),
	"hint": "\"Islam is an all-embracing religion, which should try to incorporate the obvious wisdom gained by the pagan philosophers into its own view of reality\"",
	"answer": "Islamic Aristotelians",
	"gametype": "whichperiodisthisfrom",
	"question": "Which period is this from?",
	"__v": 0
}

/* 47 */
{
	"_id": ObjectId("595d76bbd967077fc865d779"),
	"hint": "\"We can see that science is the best route to truth, and philosophy shows us the limitations of claims about perception, knowledge, truth, laws, causation, the future, morality and politics, when they are built up purely from basic sense experiences\"",
	"answer": "Empiricists",
	"gametype": "whichperiodisthisfrom",
	"question": "Which period is this from?",
	"__v": 0
}

/* 48 */
{
	"_id": ObjectId("595d76dfd967077fc865d77a"),
	"hint": "\"Reason tells us to mistrust our senses, but ideas and truth exist within the mind, and by careful thought we can build a picture of reality, using reason, maths and intuition. Science has its place within a larger spiritual and intellectual world.\"",
	"answer": "Rationalists ",
	"gametype": "whichperiodisthisfrom",
	"question": "Which period is this from?",
	"__v": 0
}

/* 49 */
{
	"_id": ObjectId("595d76fed967077fc865d77b"),
	"hint": "\"If we follow our reason far enough, we can see all ideas (and even history itself) converging on a single ideal and a single vision of the Truth, which exists in a spiritual world \"",
	"answer": "Idealists",
	"gametype": "whichperiodisthisfrom",
	"question": "Which period is this from?",
	"__v": 0
}

/* 50 */
{
	"_id": ObjectId("595d7710d967077fc865d77c"),
	"hint": "\"If we start with our sense, we realise that nothing is sure except the physical world, so we must assume that nothing else exists, either inside our own heads, or in any greater world of the spirit. The laws of science are the laws of human life.\"",
	"answer": "Materialists",
	"gametype": "whichperiodisthisfrom",
	"question": "Which period is this from?",
	"__v": 0
}